how to use EndNote in seven minutes
this video will give you a very fast
start on using EndNote it will show you
one two ways to import a reference from
an online database using PubMed as an
example
- how to create a custom group and add
references to it
three how to use find full text to try
to download PDFs for references for how
to insert a reference in a word document
five
how to format the bibliography using the
APA style as an example 6
how to add page numbers to a citation
the first method of importing is online
search in EndNote click the online
search mode button it will be the second
mode button
select the online database you want to
search
there are thousands more available these
are just the popular ones
filled your search
click the search button
the search
click the ok
select the reference
says you want in the list
click the copy to local library button
click the local library mode button to
see the contents of your EndNote library
it will be the first mode button
the references you just copied are shown
in the temporary copied references group
to create a permanent group for your
references
select create group from the group's
menu enter the name of your group and
press enter
select the references to add to the new
group and drag them into the group
another method of importing references
is direct export
i am going to import some references
from PubMed is an example but this
method can be used with many other
online databases i am using Firefox for
this example because it supports direct
export on both the windows and macintosh
platforms direct export will also work
with internet explorer
perform your search of the online
database in your browser
select the references you want to import
for pubmed mark the references to select
them
click the send to link
then so
like citation manager
different data
cases will have different ways of
selecting references and preparing them
for export this link may be called
different things by different data
providers
it may be a large button or possibly a
hyperlink in very small text it may be
called different names such as direct
export or export to citation manager
look for something that talks about
saving exporting or importing references
if offered a choice of formats
select the one that mentions endnote or
r is for pubmed selecting citation
manager will save it in the correct
format for direct export
click create file
Firefox will ask if you want to open the
file and what program you want to open
it with
select EndNote
click the ok button
if the database setup for direct export
the references will import right into
EndNote
the new references are shown in the
imported references temporary group
drag the new references to the permanent
group they should belong to
to have n no try to find the pdfs for
references
select the references
then click the find full text button
click the ok button
if any note is able to find the pdfs you
will see a paperclip icon appear by the
references
after a reference is in the EndNote
library
it can be added to a word document in
Word
click where you want to put an end note
citation then click the go to EndNote
button
select the reference or references you
want to insert
click the insert citation button
the reference is inserted into your
paper and instantly formatted
to change the style select the tiny
arrow in the bottom right corner of the
bibliography group
select the style from the list of
favorites
if your favorite style is not showing
you can use the Browse button to see
more styles
click the ok button
to add page
verse 2 a citation click on the citation
then click the edit and manage citations
button
add page numbers to the pages filled
then click the ok button
you now know two ways to import
references
one way to create a custom group one way
to put a reference in a word document
and one way to add page numbers
endnote can do a lot more than this
if you would like to learn more we have
video tutorials and full class
recordings available on our youtube
channel at www.youtube.com / and no
training
you can also register for free online
classes on our training calendar at
EndNote . com / training / calendar